so now that we have seen how tomasulo's
algorithm works and what the structures
are and so on let's go through a long
example that kind of helps you do things
on exams when we ask you kind of do
tomasulo's algorithm for a few Cycles
let's see how to do that I conveniently
came up with tables like this so that I
don't have to draw everything by hand
here we have the characteristics of our
processor basically this is that the
load unit takes two cycles to execute
the load add takes two cycles to execute
ads and subtracts multiplication will
take 10 cycles and divide will take 40
cycles and they're done in the
multiplication unit and the initial
content of R2 R3 and R4 are like this
this is the table that gives us our
instructions in order like this so this
is the very first instruction here we
will note in which cycle which
instruction issues begins execution and
writes the result this is basically our
rat this is where we will say what cycle
we are currently in and this is our
reservation stations these are the two
load reservation stations these are the
three reservation stations for the
others and this is the multiplication
units reservation stations the load
reservation stations are all really
going to be our load que so they're
going to be slightly different from the
others here we will just check when the
instruction is in a reservation station
this is going to be what the operation
is this is where we will store the value
that we have for this operand this is
the value for the second operand this is
what we are waiting for in the first
opun this is what we waiting for for the
second upun and this is whether the
instruction has been dispatched so that
we can keep track of it